Finding Aid for the Jean Renoir Papers PASC.0105
UCLA Library Special Collections
Jean Renoir papers
1915-1987
UCLA Library Special Collections
PASC.0105
56.5 linear feet (113 boxes)
20 audiovisual carriers (20 records)
0.5 linear feet (2 unprocessed vinyl record boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9927230643606533
Administrative/Biographical History
Renoir was born in Paris, France, Sept. 15, 1894; son of painter Auguste Renoir; became citizen of US, 1946, while retaining French citizenship; educated at Collége de Sainte-Croix, Neuilly-sur-Seine, Ecole Sainte-Marie de Monceau, Ecole Massina, Nice; graduated University of Aix-en-Provence with a degree in math and philosophy,1913; served in French cavalry, 1914-15; transferred to French Flying Corps, 1916; worked as potter and ceramicist, 1920-23; directed first film, La Fille de l_eau, 1924; Robert Flaherty arranged Renoir's passage to US, 1940, where he signed with 20th Century-Fox, 1941; singed with Universal, terminating contract, 1942; re-established residence in Paris, 1951, retaining his home in Beverly Hills; taught theatre at Univ. of CA, Berkeley. 1960; in addition to his film credits, he was author to numerous books and articles; Honorary Doctorate in Fine Arts, Univ. of CA, Berkeley, 1963 and Royal College of Art, London, 1971; the recipient of numerous awards, received an Oscar for Career Accomplishment, 1975; died in Beverly Hills, CA, Feb. 12, 1979.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of material related to Jean Renoir's career as director and screenwriter. Includes scripts, production material, photographs, personal and professional correspondence, and manuscript material. Photographs include film stills representing over 30 film titles released between 1926-69, photographs of Renoir's theater projects and productions, and personal photographs including family, friends, actors, and professional colleagues. Production material includes files for produced and unproduced projects from ca. 1930s-70s. Manuscript material includes novels and biographies.
Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Motion picture productions
Stage productions
Radio productions
Projects, including items not by Renoir
Publications by Renoir
Essays and articles by Jean Renoir
Notebooks
Writings about Renoir
Interviews
Photographs individuals
Photographs personal
Personal items
Miscellaneous
Correspondence
Motion picture producers and directors -- United States -- Archives.; Motion picture producers and directors -- France -- Archives.; Renoir, Jean -- Archives
- Part I - Production Files
  - Series I: MOTION PICTURE PRODUCTIONS
    - LES BAS-FONDS (1936)
      - - Production stills, b/w, (7) items (incl. dups.): Louis Jouvet, Jean Gabin, Robert LeVigan, Suzy Prim. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - LA BETE HUMAINE (1938)
      - - Script, 109 pages, n.d. "D'apres Zola." Few annotations. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - - Script, 104 pages, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - - "Scenario d'apres le roman d'Emile Zola," annotated, 87 pages, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - - Reprint from Oeuvres Completes d'Emile Zola: "Notes et Commentaires sur La Bete Humaine" par Maurice LeBlond. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - - "Resume du Scenario," 24 pages, annotated. - Handwritten list of credits, 3 pages. - Program for "Desirs Humains," adapted by Fritz Lang, incl. handwritten comparative notes by Jean Renoir (?). (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - - "Liste des Dialogues du Film", 30 pages, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - - Handwritten list/index of folder contents. - List of scenes (5 pages). - List of exterior shots and locations (18 pages). - Scene description with dialogue/action (39 pages). - Notes on scenes regarding script and novel (16 pages). (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - - Articles regarding production and release of the film, October 1938 - May 1939. (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w, (24) items, incl. Simone Simon, Jean Gabin, Fernand Ledoux, Claude Renoir, Julien Carette, Blanchette Brunoy, and cast and crew. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - BOUDU SAUVE DES EAUX (1932)
      - - Production stills, off-camera shots, b/w, (11) items, incl. Michel Simon, Marcelle Haina, Titta Ruffo, Severine Lezinska, and Charles Graudval. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - LE CAPORAL EPINGLE (1962)
      - - Annotated script, 181 pages, 9/20/61, includes extensive revisions, many insertions and pages crossed out. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - - Script for sequences I, II, V - VIII. 169 pages, 8/1/61. Some annotatations, some inserts. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - - Scripts for sequences I-VIII, 151 pages, 9/1/61. Some annotations. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - - Script (photocopied). 177 pages, n.d. "Les Films du Cyclope presentent un film de Jean Renoir..d'apres le roman de Jacques Perret."Dist. Consortium Pathe-Paris. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - - Three notebooks with handwritten notes, n.d. - Communique concerning publicity strategy from E. Harris, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - - Treatment, 50 pages, January 1961, mimeographed/offprint, including corrections. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - - Off-camera shots, b/w, (9) items, incl. Jean Renoir and crew. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - LE CARROSSE D'OR (1952)
      - - Annotated typed story outline in English entitled "Columbine and her Mask," dated 2/18/53 and 2/20/53, 14 pages, 2 copies each. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - - "'The Golden Coach' - The First Treatment de Jean Renoir (sic)." Panaria Film, Roma. Includes notes and annotations, 57 pages, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - - Dialogue for scenes 101-316 in French, 18 pages. - Narration (epilogue), additional lines, in English and French. - Dialogue for scenes 1525a-1526 in English. (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - - Shooting script (mimeographed/offprint), 205 pages, annotated. In English. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - - J.R.'s schedule for interviews and appointments 9/30-10/21 (4 pages). - Insurance policy (5 pages), 1952. - Contract (unsigned) with Panaria Film, Roma (4 pages). - Notes on dubbing and sound effects (2 pages). (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w, (47) items, incl. J.R., Anna Magnani, Jean Debucourt, Claude Renoir, Joseph de Bretagne, and Mario Chiari. (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - CATHERINE (UNE VIE SANS JOIE) (1924)
      - - J.R.'s notes concerning expenses, 1 page, n.d. - Arbitration contract between J.R., Pierre Braunberger and Albert Dieudonne concerning the rights to the film, signed, dated 12/10/26, 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - - Newspaper article re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - CHARLESTON (SUR UN AIR DE CHARLESTON) (1926)
      - - Production stills, b/w, (6) items, incl. Catherine Hessling and Johnny Huggins. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - LA CHIENNE (1931)
      - - Production stills, b/w, (6) items, incl. Georges Flamant, Michel Simon, Janie Marese, and Madeleine Berubet. (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - - Script published in "L'Avant-Scene Cinema," no. 162, October 1975. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - LE CRIME DE MONSIEUR LANGE (1935)
      - - Handwritten and typed notes, scenes, and dialogue, 63 pages, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - - "Histoire de Jean Renoir - dialogues de Jacques Prevert," 9 pages, n.d. - Scenario by Jean Renoir and Jean Castanier entitled "L'Ascension de Monsieur Lange" ("titre provisoire"), 11 pages + title page, dated 6/6/35. 2 items total. (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - - Production stills, b/w, (20) items, incl. Jules Berry, Rene Lefevre, Sylvia Bataille, Florelle, Marcel Levesque, Maurice Baquet and cast. (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - LE DEJEUNER SUR L'HERBE (1959)
      - - Typed script with changes and annotations, "Scenario original de Jean Renoir," 167 pages, n.d. (handwritten note added: "dialogues de Jean Renoir"). (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - - Script, 167 pages, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - - Article (typed) by J.R., in French, labeled "Article pour le N.Y. Herald Tribune," 5 pages. - Handwritten draft of same, dated 10/1/60, 10 pages. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - - Story outline, 32 pages. - Deposit receipt, Association des Auteurs de Films, Paris, 6/9/1958. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - - Dialogue script, 60 pages, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - - "Scenario original" (script), spiralbound notebook, 167 pages. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - - Annotated script, carbon copy, 127 pages, 1/11/59. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - - "Scenario original": annotated script, first version, 137 pages, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - - Breakdown of footage for sequences 1-10. 2 pages. - Credits, 3 pages. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - - Two notebooks, handwritten: one entitled "Dejeuner," the other "Dejeuner, 1/1/59" and "Nouveau Projet, 11 August 1959." (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - - Article (oversize) in "Jour de France" about the film, 4 pages, 7/18/59. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w and color, (41) items, incl. Charles Blavette, Marguerite Cassan, Catherine Rouvel, Paul Meurisse, and J.R. (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - DIARY OF A CHAMBERMAID (1946)
      - - Copy for music scenes #103 and 203 by Michel Michelet, 1 item. - Copy of handwritten poem by J.R., 1 item. - Text of AP News Features, Hollywood Shorts, Sunday August 19, 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - - Annotated script ("first rough screen play"), in English, 190 pages, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, incl. J.R., Paulette Goddard, Francis Lederer, b/w, (16) items. (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - ELENA ET LES HOMMES (1956)
      - - Contract between Franco London Films and Berkshire Pictures Corporation, dated October 31, 1955, 16 pages. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - - Receipt and letter for submitting manuscript entitled "L'Oeillet Rouge" to Association des Auteurs de Films, August 22, 1995. - Carbon copy of synopsis, 12 pages. (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - - Notebook entitled "Generalites," including notes on "Elena et les hommes." (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - - Script, entitled "Elliena," 208 pages, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - - Script entitled "Elliena et les Hommes," 191 pages, n.d., offprint/mimeographed. Prod. Franco London Film S.A. & Les Films Gibe. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - - Dialogue script, "Elena," in English ("dialogue anglais"), offprint/mimeographed, 7/9/56, 59 pages. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - - Lyrics, both handwritten and typed, by J.R. for six music numbers by Joseph Kosma, 11/22/55, annotated, 26 items. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - - Texts by J.R: "Commentaire Film Television" (3 pgs), "Commentaire Court Metrage" (4 pgs), "Presentation Du Film Aux Spectateurs" (2 pgs), "Suggested newsreel interview with Ingrid Bergman" (5 pgs). Credits, interview schedules, misc. Total 20 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - - Articles from various journals re: Ingrid Bergman and the film, 1945-1957. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w, (83) items, incl. Ingrid Bergman, Joseph Kosma, Magali Noel, Jean Claudio, and J.R., cast and crew. (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - - Off-camera shots, b/w, (2) items, Ingrid Bergman, Mel Ferrer. (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - - Script, in English, 210 pages, marked "March 1956," mimeographed/offprint. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - - Offprint/mimeographed working script in French, 211 pages, dated 2/28/56, with extensive pencilled-in annotations and revisions. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - LA FILLE DE L'EAU (1925)
      - - Contracts for the sale of the film for U.S.A., dated 1925. - Telegram and reply to H. van Doren re film rights (3 items). - Article "Renoir Before Boudu: La Fille de L'Eau and Nana" by John Belton in Bright Lights, No. 5, 1977. Total 9 items. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - - (1) production still, b/w, of Catherine Hessling. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - FRENCH CANCAN (1954)
      - - Handwritten and typed/mimeographed versions of song lyrics for the film, lyrics by J.R. - Sheet music for "La Complainte de la Butte" (film theme), 3 editions. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - - Undated scenario, 23 pages, n.d. - Cinema receipt for expenses, dated 1/7/55. - Handwritten notebook by J.R. (also includes notes on projects: GASPARD, LA LUTTE CONTRE LES CONVENTIONS, ROSARIO). (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w, (69) items, incl. Francoise Arnoul, Jean Gabin, Maria Felix, and Dido Freire Renoir with J. R. (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - - (8) colored photographs, oversized. - Sheet music for "Complainte de la Butte." (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - - Screenplay, 191 pages, in English, n.d., offprint/mimeographed. (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - - Scenario published in "Tele-cine", no 50, July/August 1955, pp.1-2, followed by "French Cancan": Un Divertissement?" a critical dicussion by Jean Collet, pp. 3-10. (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - LA GRANDE ILLUSION (1937)
      - - Dialogue scripts in French, 37 pages. - Script of German subtitles, 20 pages. (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - - List of the film's awards, 1 page, (2 copies), n.d. - Box office figures after 10 weeks in Paris, Bordeaux, Lille, Lyon, Marseille, Strasbourg, Toulouse, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - - Letter and receipt for the deposit of the script with the Association des Auteurs de films, December 1935. (5 receipts, 3 letters). (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - - Annotated text for insert to program for the re-release screening at the Sorbonne, 4 pages, 2/10/58. - Articles and transcribed copies of articles, 1937-1958, about the film's release in 1937 and re-release in 1958. (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - - Production stills, b/w, 47 items, incl. Jean Gabin, Erich von Stroheim, Pierre Fresnais, Sylvain Itkine, Marcel Dalio, Julien Carette, Gaston Modot, Jean Daste, Werner Florian, and cast. - Paris Opening Night group shots, w/J.R. and others, 8 items (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazine re: the film. (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - - Script published in "L'Avant-Scene Cinema," January 1965, no. 44. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - MADAME BOVARY (1933)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w, (6) items, incl. Valentine Tessier, cast and crew. (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - LA MARSEILLAISE (1937)
      - - Draft of script: description of scenes/shots #1-138, action, characters, location, and special props. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - - "Projet de Scenario" (Summary and sequence of scenes in 5[6] parts):I. Actualites. II. Les Etats Generaux. III. Episodes des Femmes a Versailles. IV. Worms. VI bis. Avant Varennes. V. Varennes. 18 pages, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - - Program, Kosmofilm, Sweden, n.d. - Leaflets for screenings in France, 2 items. - Lyrics for "O Louis! Mon Roi!" - Letter re Cinematheque screening conditions, 3 pgs. - Salary figures, 2 pgs. - "Copie des Extraits du Contract," June, 1937, 1 page. (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - - "Tableau synoptique des situations et des evenements dans le cadre du film" (4 pages). - Script materials, 6 scenes. - Research materials: anecdotes, quotes, notes on Parisian life: dress, hair, food, games, etc., three speeches by Robespierre. (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - - Notebook of extensive historical research arranged by topics [similar to the script synopsis in folder 11]. (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w, (8) items, incl. Lise Delamare, Pierre Renoir, Louis Jouvet, Edmond Ardisson, Nadia Sibirskaia. (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - NANA (1926)
      - - Contracts for the sale of the film in European countries, South America and Japan, 1926, 1927. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - - Handwritten "scenario," 151 pages. (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - - Contract, with Delog Film, Berlin, re shooting and distribution in Germany, 2 pages, 3 September, 1925. [Signed by Jean Renoir and Claude Renoir]. (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - - Scrapbook containing various press clippings relating to the film, 2/20/26-7/1/26. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - - Production stills, b/w, (16) items, incl. J. R., Catherine Hessling, and Pierre Champagne. (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazine re: the film. - Copy of letter from Denise LeBlond-Zola re American adaptation of "Nana" in 1934, 4 pgs. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - LA NUIT DU CARREFOUR (1932)
      - - Production still, b/w, of Pierre Renoir and Winna Winfried, 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - - Magazine article/clipping and program for festival screening, 2 items. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - ON PURGE BEBE (1931)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w, (7) items, of cast and crew incl. Claude Heymann (assistant director), Fernandel, and Michel Simon. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - LA P'TITE LILI (1927)
      - - Production stills, b/w, two scenes with J.R. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - UNE PARTIE DE CAMPAGNE (1936)
      - - Scenario by Jacques Prevert, 107 pages, 4/3/27. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - - Scripts with some annotations, dated 6/8/36, 82 pages, (2 copies.) (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - - Partial script, pages 108-145 and 131-179. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - - Scenario/treatments, some annotated: - Undated, 25 pages. - Dated II/5/36, 30 pages (3 copies). - Dated 22/8/35, 19 pages. - Dated 4/5/36, 22 pages). - Dated 27/4/36, 21 pages. - Dated 5/5/36, 9 pages (3 copies). (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - - Summaries/outlines: By H. Weissmann, 12/II/36, 6 pages. - Theme Commercial, 5 pages (incomplete). - "Projet de continuite (texte de Brunius d'apres J. Prevert)", dated 4/12/36, 6 pages, and dated 4/I/37, 16 pages. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - - Scenarios/scene breakdown, with annotations: dated 27/4/36, 21 pages. - Undated, 8 pages. - Decoupage de scenario, dated 4/5/36, 9 pages (3 copies). (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - - Notes and ideas, dated 26/II/36. - Notes on cast. - Budget figures. - Location breakdown. - Notes for directing (mise en scene), - Additonal pages 18bis, 18ter. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - - Handwritten script, scenario, notes. Various pagination, not collated. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - - Press booklets for the film, in German, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, 16 items, incl. Sylvia Bataille, Jeanne Marken, Jacques Brunius (Jacques Borel), Georges Darnoux and Paul Temps. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - - Articles in newspapers and magazines re: the film. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - LE PETIT THEATRE DE JEAN RENOIR (1969)
      - - Scenarios: - "C'est la Revolution," 31 pages. - "Creme de Beaute,"24 pages. - "Le Roi d'Yvetot," 49 pages. - "La Cireuse Electrique," 22 pages. -"La Guerre," 43 pages. (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - - "C'est la Revolution: Film en Sept Chapitres," scenario, 159 pages: "La Duchesse," "L'Anniversaire," "Creme de Beaute," "La Grande Cuisine," "Le Roi D'Yvetot," "La Cireuse Electrique," "La Guerre". (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - - "C'est la Revolution." Individual scenarios: "La Grande Cuisine." "Les Blancs." "L' Heroisme." "La Chasse." "E. A. Poe." "Bebert." "Le Quatorze Juillet." "Le Caporal" (2 copies). "La Guerre," 3 typed and 12 ms. pages. Undated. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - - "C'est la Revolution." Handwritten and typed drafts of "La Grande Cuisine," "Les Blancs," "L'Heroisme," "Edgar Poe," "Creme de Beaute" (2 version), "La Chasse" (2 versions), "Bebert". (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - - "C'est la Revolution": Budget figures and breakdown (4 pgs) (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - - "C'est la Revolution," notebook with handwritten note, "Scenario original de J.R.," 29 pages. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - - "Le Dernier Reveillon": Script materials in French and English. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - - "La Cireuse Electrique": script materials in French and English. (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - - "La Cireuse Electrique": script materials in French. (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - - "Le Cireuse Electrique": script materials in French with handwritten annotations. (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - - "Quand L'Amour Meurt": Sheet music, lyrics in English, 2 pages, n.d. - Introductory note. - Newspaper clipping. (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - - English language dubbing/timing script with corrections, 3 pages. - Program notes: by Herman G. Weinberg, 3 pages, 2 copies, and by Joel Reisner, 10 pages. (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - - "Le Roi d'Yvetot": script materials in French and English. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - - "Le Roi d'Yvetot": script materials in English and French. - Handwriten notes, 7 pages. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - - Correspondence related to American screening dates, 1970-73. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - - Two versions of "La Duchesse," in typescript: 23-page version, 2 copies, 31-page version, 1 copy. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - - "La Petite Pomme d'Api," two scripts, one dated 2/26/69. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - - "La Guerre." Three scripts with annotations. - Handwritten notes, 6 pages and 4 pages. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - - "Creme de Beaute," three scripts. - Handwritten notes, loose pages. (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - - "Le Retour Aux Sources," script dated 2/26/69. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - - "Le Roi d'Yvetot," 2 scripts, dated 2/26/69 & 1/5/69 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - - "Le Roi d'Yvetot": 2 typed scripts, undated. (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - - Handwritten musical score for "Le Cireuse Electrique" by Joseph Kosma and J.R., n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - - Production stills and off-camera shots, b/w and color, (18) items, incl. J.R., Jeanne Moreau, and cast and crew. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - - "Le Dernier Reveillon": (89) snapshots of J. R., cast and crew. - "Le Roi d'Yvetot": (33) snapshots of J. R., cast and crew. - "La Cireuse Electrique": (49) snapshots of cast. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - - Articles from newspapers and magazines re: the productions. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - LA PETITE MARCHANDE D'ALLUMETTES (1928)
      - - Receipt for the deposit of the scenario with accompanying confirmation letter, 2/22/27. 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - - Production stills, b/w, (6) items, incl. Catherine Hessling. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - LA REGLE DU JEU (1939)
      - - Annotated script materials, arranged by scenes, including: duplicates, versions of scenes (including scenes not in released film]. - Outline of scenes, handwritten and typed, total 286 pages, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - - Handwritten notes by Dido Freire possibly relating to the film. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - - Scenario, "Les Caprices de Marianne," 3 pages, 2 copies, n.d. - Receipts for the deposit of the scenarios "Les Femmes Sont Comme Ca" (11/14/38) and "La Regle du Jeu" (2/1/39). (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - - Scenario, 11/12/38, 3 pages. - Scenario, 3 pages, December 1938. - Scenario with cast list, 6 pages, n.d. - Scenario, 3 pages, n.d. - Proposed cast list and character sketches, 2 pages, n.d. - Scenario/scenes 1-11, 16 pages. (Box 9, Folder 9)